Every can of soup, every piece of meat, every T-shirt. We as humans, right now, are destroying the only thing we really need to survive: our planet. And most of the horrible problems that we're facing today, like climate change and modern slavery in supply chains, come down to decisions. Human decisions to produce something one way and not another. And that's how we, as consumers, end up making decisions that harm the planet or our fellow humans. By choosing the wrong products. But I refuse to believe that anybody here in this room, or frankly, anybody on this planet, really wants to buy a product that harms the planet or our fellow humans
Cada lata de sopa, cada trozo de carne, cada camiseta. Como humanos, ahora mismo, estamos destruyendo lo único que necesitamos para sobrevivir: nuestro planeta. Y la mayoría de los problemas horribles a los que hacemos frente hoy, como el cambio climático y la esclavitud moderna en cadenas de montaje, vienen de decisiones. Decisiones humanas de producir algo de una forma y no de otra. Y así es como, como consumidores, acabamos tomando decisiones que dañan el planeta o a nuestros colegas humanos. Eligiendo productos incorrectos. Pero me niego a creer que cualquiera en esta sala, o francamente, cualquiera en este planeta, realmente quiera comprar un producto, que dañe el planeta o a los humanos
if given the choice. But you see, choice is a loaded word. Choice means there's another option. Choice means you can afford that option. But choice also means you have enough information to make an informed decision. And that information nowadays simply just doesn't exist. Or at least it's really, really hard to access. But I think this is about to change. Because we can use technology to solve this information problem. And many of the specific technologies that we need to do that have become better and cheaper over the recent years, and are now ready to be used at scale. So, over the past two years, my team and I have been working with one of the world's largest conservation organizations, WWF, and we've founded a company called OpenSC, where SC stands for supply chain. And we believe that by using technology we can help to create transparency and traceability in supply chains, and through that, help to completely revolutionize the way that we buy and also produce products as humans. Now, some of this is going to sound a little bit like science fiction, but it's already happening. Let me explain. So, in order to solve this information problem, we need to do three things: verify, trace and share. Verify specific sustainability and ethical production claims in a data-based and automated way. Then trace those individual physical products throughout their supply chains, and finally, share that information with consumers in a way that truly gives them a choice and lets them make consumption decisions that are more aligned with their values. I'm going to use a real product and a supply chain where we've made all of this a reality already: a Patagonian toothfish, or Chilean sea bass, as it's called in the US. Number one, verify. Verify how something is produced. But not just by saying, "Trust me, this is good, trust me, we've done all the right things," but by producing evidence for that individual physical product, and the way it was produced. By producing evidence for a specific sustainability or ethical production claim. So for example, in the case of the fish, has this fish been caught in an area where there's enough of them, so that it's sustainable to catch it there and not in a marine protected area? So what we're doing here is we're taking almost real-time GPS data from the ship -- the ship that's fishing -- and that tells us where the ship is and where it's going at what speed. And we can then combine that with other types of data, like, for example, how deep the sea floor is.
si se le da la elección. Pero verán, elección es una palabra de peso. Elección significa que hay otra opción. Elección significa que pueden permitirse esa opción. Pero elección también significa que tiene suficiente información para tomar una decisión informada. Y esa información a día de hoy simplemente no existe. O al menos es de muy difícil acceso. Pero creo que esto está a punto de cambiar. Porque podemos usar la tecnología para solucionar este problema. Y muchos de los aspectos tecnológicos que necesitamos para hacerlo se han vuelto mejores y más baratos en los últimos años, y ahora están listos para usarse a gran escala. En los dos últimos años, mi equipo y yo hemos trabajado con una de las mayores organizaciones de conservación del mundo, la WWF, y fundamos una compañía llamada OpenSC, donde SC significa "cadena de suministro". Y creemos que usando la tecnología podemos ayudar a crear transparencia y trazabilidad en las cadenas de suministro y a través de eso, ayudar a revolucionar completamente la manera en que vendemos y también producimos como humanos. Bien, algunas cosas van a sonar un poco a ciencia ficción, pero ya está ocurriendo. Déjenme explicarles. Para solucionar este problema de información, necesitamos hacer tres cosas: verificar, rastrear y compartir. Verificar la sostenibilidad específica y la proclamada producción ética en una base de datos y de manera automática. Después rastrear estos productos físicos individuales en las cadenas de suministro, y finalmente, compartir esa información con consumidores de forma que realmente les dé una elección y les permita tomar decisiones de consumo que mejor se ajusten a sus valores. Voy a usar un producto real y una cadena de suministro donde hemos hecho esto realidad: la merluza negra patagónica o bacalao chileno, como es llamado en EE. UU. Número uno: verificar. Verificar cómo es producido algo. Pero no solo diciendo: "Confía en mí, esto es bueno, confía en mí, hemos hecho todo bien", sino creando una evidencia para ese producto físico y la forma en que es producido. Creando una evidencia para un producto específico proclamado sostenible y ético. Así que, por ejemplo, en el caso del pescado, ¿ha sido capturado en un área donde hay suficientes, para que sea sostenible atraparlo allí y no en un área marina protegida? Lo que estamos haciendo aquí es tomar los datos del GPS del barco casi a tiempo real, el barco que está pescando, y nos dice dónde está el barco y dónde va, a qué velocidad. Y entonces podemos combinar eso con otros tipos de datos, como, por ejemplo, cuán profundo es el lecho marino.
And combining all of this information, our machine-learning algorithms can then verify, in an automated way, whether the ship is only fishing where it's supposed to, or not. And as sensors become cheaper, we can put them in more places. And that means we can capture more data, and combining that with advancements in data science, it means that we can now verify
Y combinando toda esta información, nuestra máquina de aprendizaje de algoritmos puede verificar, automáticamente, si el barco solo pesca donde se supone o no. Y como los sensores se han vuelto baratos, podemos colocarnos en más sitios. Y eso significa que podemos capturar más datos y combinarlos con los avances en la ciencia de la información, que significa que ahora podemos verificar
specific sustainability and ethical production claims in an automated, real-time and ongoing manner. And that really lays the basis for this information revolution. So, number two, trace. Trace those individual physical products, so that we can truly say that the claim that we've verified about a certain product actually belongs to that individual product that we as consumers have right in front of us. Because without that level of traceability, all that we've really verified in the first place is that somebody, somewhere, at some point caught a fish in a sustainable way, or didn't harm the employee when asking them to produce a T-shirt, or didn't use pesticides when growing a vegetable that didn't actually need it. Only if I give a product an identity from the start and then trace it throughout the whole supply chain, can this claim and the value that's been created by producing it in the right way truly stay with it. Now, I've talked about cheaper sensors. There are many other technological developments that make all of this much more possible today than every before. For example, the falling costs of tags. You give a product a name, a serial number, an identity, the tag is its passport. What you can see here is a toothfish being caught. This is what's called a longline fishery, so the fish are coming up onto the boat on individual hooks. And as soon as the fish is on board, it is killed, and then after that, we insert a small tag into the fish's flesh. And in that tag, there is an RFID chip with a unique serial number, and that tag follows the fish throughout the whole supply chain and makes it really easy to sense its presence at any port, on any truck or in any processing plant. But consumers can't really read RFID tags. And so, when it comes to filleting and packaging the fish, we read the RFID tag and then remove it. And then we add a unique QR code to the packaging of the fish. And that QR code then points back to the same information that we've verified about the fish in the first place. And so, depending on the type of product that we're working with, we may use QR codes, bar codes, RFID tags or other tag technologies. But there are also technologies that are at the brink of large-scale breakthrough that make tags themselves obsolete. Like, for example, analyzing a product for trace elements that can then tell you quite accurately where it is actually from.
productos específicos proclamados sostenibles y éticos de forma automatizada, en tiempo real y continua. Y realmente eso sienta las bases de esta revolución informativa. Número dos: rastrear. Rastrear esos productos físicos individuales de manera que podamos realmente decir que la afirmación que hemos verificado sobre un producto de hecho, pertenece a ese producto individual que como consumidores tenemos frente a nosotros. Porque sin ese nivel de trazabilidad todo lo que hemos verificado en primer lugar es que alguien, en algún lado, en algún momento capturó un pez de forma sostenible o no perjudicó al empleado cuando les pidió producir una camiseta, o no usó pesticidas que de hecho no necesitaba cuando cultivó un vegetal. Solo si le doy una identidad a un producto desde el principio y lo rastreo a lo largo de la cadena de suministro se puede mantener la afirmación y el valor que dice tener al producirse de forma correcta. Bien, he hablado sobre los sensores baratos. Hay muchos otros desarrollos tecnológicos que hacen que todo esto sea mucho más posible hoy que nunca. Por ejemplo, la bajada de costos de etiquetas. Se le da a un producto un nombre, un número de serie, una identidad, su etiqueta es su pasaporte. Lo que pueden ver aquí es una merluza negra siendo capturada. Esto es lo que se llama pesca de palangre, los peces entran en el bote en anzuelos individuales. Y tan pronto como el pez está a bordo, se le mata, y tras eso, insertamos una pequeña etiqueta dentro de su carne. En esa etiqueta hay un chip RFID con un número de serie único que acompaña al pez a lo largo de la cadena de suministro y hace muy sencillo detectar su presencia en cualquier puerto, camión o planta de procesado. Pero los consumidores no pueden leer las etiquetas RFID. Y así, cuando se filetea y empaqueta el pescado, leemos la RFID y la quitamos. Y entonces añadimos un código QR único para empaquetar el pescado. Y ese código QR señala la misma información que hemos verificado sobre el pescado en primer lugar. Y así, dependiendo del tipo de producto con el que trabajamos, podemos usar códigos QR, códigos de barras, etiquetas RFID u otra tecnología de etiquetado. Pero también hay tecnologías que están al borde de la expansión a gran escala que dejan a las etiquetas obsoletas. Como, por ejemplo, analizar un producto para rastrear elementos que pueden decir con precisión de dónde vienen.
Then there's blockchain. A decentralized technology can act as a catalyst for this revolution. Because it can help mitigate some of the trust issues that are inherent to giving people information and then asking them to change their consumption behavior because of that information. And so, we use blockchain technology where it adds value to what we're doing. But importantly, we don't let the limitations that this technology still has today, like, for example, with regards to scaling, we don't let that stand in our way. And that brings us to the third point. Share. How to share the information that we've verified and tracked about where a product is from, how it was produced and how it got to where it is? How to share this information is really different from product to product. And different from where you buy it. You behave differently in those situations. You are stressed and time-poor in the supermarket. Or with short attention span over dinner, because your date is so cute. Or you are critical and inquisitive when researching for a larger purchase online. And so for our fish, we've developed a digital experience that works when buying the fish in a freezer in a fish specialty store and that gives you all of the information about the fish and its journey. But we also worked with a restaurant and developed a different digital experience that only summarizes the key facts about the fish and its journey, and works better in a dinner setting and, hopefully, there doesn't annoy your date too much. Now, that brings us full circle. We've verified that the fish was caught in an area where it's sustainable to do so. We've then traced it throughout the entire supply chain to maintain its identity and all the information that's attached to it. And then, we've shared that information with consumers
Luego está el blockchain. Una tecnología descentralizada que puede actuar como catalizador de esta revolución. Porque puede ayudar a mitigar algunas cuestiones de confianza que son inherentes al dar información a la gente y entonces pedirles cambiar sus hábitos de consumo debido a esa información. Y así, usamos la tecnología blockchain donde damos más valor a lo que hacemos. Pero, más importante, no permitimos que las limitaciones que aún tiene esta tecnología, como, por ejemplo, respecto a la escala, se interpongan en nuestro camino. Y eso nos lleva al tercer punto. Compartir. ¿Cómo compartimos la información que hemos verificado y rastreado sobre de dónde es el producto, cómo fue producido y cómo llegó a donde está? Cómo compartimos esta información es muy diferente de producto a producto. Y diferente según dónde lo compre. Uds. se comportan de forma diferente en estas situaciones. Están estresados y tienen poco tiempo en el supermercado. O con poca atención durante la cena porque su cita es una belleza. O son críticos e inquisitivos cuando investigan para hacer una compra grande en línea. Así que, para nuestro pescado, hemos desarrollado una experiencia digital que funciona cuando compramos pescado congelado en una pescadería que le da toda la información sobre el pescado y su viaje. Pero también funciona con un restaurante y desarrolla una experiencia digital diferente que solo resume hechos clave sobre el pescado y su viaje y funciona mejor en una cena, y, con suerte, no molesta mucho a su cita. Bien, eso cierra el ciclo. Hemos verificado que el pescado fue capturado en un área donde es sostenible hacerlo. Luego lo hemos rastreado en una cadena de suministro que mantiene su identidad y toda información asociada. Y hemos compartido esa información con consumidores
in a way that gives them a choice and lets them make consumption decisions
de forma que les da una elección y permite que tomen decisiones de consumo
that are more in line with their values. Now, for this fish example, this is already rolled out at scale. This season, the entire fleet of the world's largest toothfish fishing company, Austral Fisheries, is tagging every single fish that they catch and that ends up in their premium branded "Glacier 51" product. And you can already buy this fish. And with it, you can have all of the information I talked about today, and much more, attached to each individual fish or portion of the fish that you may buy. But this is not a fish or seafood thing. We're working on many, many different commodities and products and their supply chains across the globe. From dairy to fruit and vegetables, to nonfood products made out of wood. As a consumer, all of this may sound like a huge burden, because you don't have time to look at all of this information every time you buy something. And I don't expect you to, because you'll have help with that. In the future, we'll leave the decision of which specific product to buy increasingly up to machines. An algorithm will know enough about you
que se ajustan más con sus valores. Para el pez de este ejemplo esto ya está implementado a gran escala. Esta temporada, la flota entera de la mayor compañía de pesca de merluza negra, Austral Fisheries, ha etiquetado cada pescado que han capturado y esto termina en el producto de su marca premiada "Glacier 51". Y ya pueden comprar este pescado. Y con esto, todos podemos tener la información de la que hablé hoy, y mucho más, unida a cada pescado individual o porción de pescado que puedan comprar. Pero esto no es solo cosa del pescado o el marisco. Sino que trabajamos con muchos servicios y productos diferentes y sus cadenas de suministro a lo largo del globo. Desde lácteos a frutas y verduras, hasta productos no comestibles hechos de madera. Como consumidor, todo esto puede sonar como una molestia enorme porque no tenemos tiempo para mirar toda esa información cada vez que compramos algo. Y no espero que lo hagan, porque tendrán ayuda para eso. En el futuro, dejaremos cada vez más la decisión sobre qué producto específico comprar a las máquinas. Un algoritmo sabrá suficiente sobre Uds.
to make those decisions for you, so you don't have to. And maybe it will even do a better job at it. In a recent study, 85 percent of those buying a product through a virtual assistant said that they, on occasion, actually went with the top product recommendation of that virtual assistant, rather than the specific product or brand that they set out to buy in the first place. You just say you need toilet paper, it's then an algorithm that decides which brand, price point or whether you go with recycled or not. Well, nowadays this is usually based on what you bought in the past, or whoever pays the most to the company behind the virtual assistant. But why shouldn't that be also based on your values? Knowing that you want to buy planet-friendly and knowing whether and how much you're willing and able to pay for that. Now, that will make it easy and seamless, but still based on granular effects and data to choose the right products. Not by necessarily doing it yourself but by asking an algorithm that knows how much you care about this planet. Not by necessarily doing it yourself but by asking an algorithm that is never time-poor or distracted, or with short attention span because of the cute date, and that knows how much you care about this planet and the people living on it, by asking that algorithm to look at all of that information for you and to decide for you. If we have reliable and trustworthy information like that and the right systems that make use of it, consumers will support those who are doing the right thing by producing products in a sustainable and ethical way. They will support them every time by choosing their goods over others. And that means that good producers and processors and retailers
para tomar las decisiones por Uds., así que no tendrán que hacerlo. Y quizás haga incluso un mejor trabajo. En un estudio reciente, el 85 % de aquellos que compraron un producto con un asistente virtual, dijeron que, en ocasiones, eligieron la recomendación del producto estrella de ese asistente virtual más que un producto o marca específica que pretendían comprar en primer lugar. Ud. dijo que necesitaba papel higiénico, entonces hay un algoritmo que decide qué marca, señala el precio o si le va el reciclaje o no. Hoy en día normalmente está basado en qué compró en el pasado, o en quién paga más a la compañía detrás del asistente virtual. Pero ¿por qué no debería basarse también en sus valores? Sabiendo que quiere comprar sosteniblemente y sabiendo si y cuánto está dispuesto a pagar por eso. Eso lo hará fácil y sin problemas pero escoger los productos correctos aún estará basado en efectos granulares y datos. No necesariamente haciéndolo Ud. mismo, sino preguntando a un algoritmo que sabe cuánto se preocupa por el planeta. No necesariamente haciéndolo Ud. mismo, sino preguntando a un algoritmo al que nunca le falta tiempo o se distrae o con poco nivel de atención por una cita y sabe cuánto se preocupa por este planeta, por la gente que vive en él, pidiendo a ese algoritmo buscar toda la información por Ud. y decidiendo por Ud. Si tenemos una fuente de información valiosa y confiable como esa y los sistemas correctos para usarla, los consumidores apoyarán a aquellos que hacen lo correcto produciendo productos de una forma sostenible y ética. Los apoyarán cada vez eligiendo sus productos por delante de otros. Y eso significa que bienes, productores, procesadores y minoristas
will get rewarded. And bad actors will be forced to adjust their practices or get out of business. And we need that.
serán recompensados. Y los agentes perjudiciales serán forzados a ajustar sus prácticas o dejar el negocio. Y necesitamos eso.
If we want to continue to live together on this beautiful planet, we really need it. Thank you. (Applause)
Si queremos continuar viviendo juntos en este bello planeta, realmente lo necesitamos. Gracias. (Aplausos)